

Gonzalo Varela

Developer Sr.

Phone: +54 911 - 6864 - 0435

gonzalo.varela1981@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/gonzalo-varela-85815320/

Summary

I am a software developer with experience in SQL Postgres + PostGIS databases and Python + Django. Specialized in GIS software with a working experience implementing and maintaining Geoserver and Geonode platforms. I had also work extensively with Leafletjs, MapboxGL and VectorTile server. I am open to work as part of a team or individually.

Key Technologies

Python + Django, PostgreSQL, Geoserver, Geonetwork, GeoJSON, PHP, QGIS

Languages

English - Intermediate

Habilities and Technologies

PostgreSQL, SQL/PL-SQL

PostGIS

Python + Django

Geoserver, Geonetwork, Geonode, QGIS

PHP

Bash, CSS, jQuery, HTML 5, LeafLetJS

Problem solving

Linux, Windows, MySQL, Programming, Code Igniter (framework mvc para PHP)

Development, Web Services

Education / Courses

UNTREF University (2019 – Present day)

Bachelor in GIS (Geographic Information System)

FIUBA graduates center (2018)

Python for developers

FOSS4G-AR

Geonetwork Introduction (2018)

Advanced Geonetwork – Code Personalization (2019) Advanced Geoserver – Cluster and Load Balancing over Docker (2019) PGRouting (2018)

Educación IT

Java Essentials (2010) PHP Web Services (2011)

Work Experience

Technical Lead / Developer / SIG Consultant at SSPPBE - GCBA (Buenos Aires City government)April 2021 – Present day

In April 2021 I assumed the role of both Developer and Technical Leader not only for the experience in Geographic Information Systems but also due to my abilities to anticipate and solve problems

April 2020 - Present day

I started as a Developer Ssr. and began to assume a Sr. role slowly, getting involved in models design, code revision and helping pushing forward halted processes in pair coding sessions.

Some highlight projects are:

- 1 Back-end design (API-Taxi con Django + Postgres + PostGIS) https://ruteo.usig.buenosaires.gob.ar/pie/viaroute?loc=-34.4873995,-58.684607&loc=-34.5009963,-58.6760981&instructions=true
- 2 Debug and Expand functionalities API Catastro (Python + Django) https://epok.buenosaires.gob.ar/catastro/
- 3 Functionality updates API Ciudad3D (Python + Django) https://ciudad3d.buenosaires.gob.ar
- 4 Back-end update (Gestor de Datos Geográficos con Django + Postgres + PostGIS) https://epok.buenosaires.gob.ar/pub/mapa/mapaescolar/establecimientos_educativos/
- 5 Implementation and Maintenance Vector Tile Server (Python + sqlite)
- 6 Documentation and Tutorial reviews
- 7 Docker images creation from scratch or update
- 8 File uploads and metadata updates automation to Open Data Portal (python + CKAN)

- 9 Geospatial Data analysis (PostGIS + QGIS, adress normalization, 3DCity visualization)
- 10 Process normalization (Map of crime) https://mapa.seguridadciudad.gob.ar/

Developer / Freelance Consultant

March 2015 - March 2020

I worked independently for a few years in challenging and innovating projects. Some remarkable companies and/or institutions I had the opportunity to work include:

- National Institute of Geography (Branch of Defense department)
- ScanTerra S.A. (Geographic data analysis for Agriculture)

Some highlight projects I had participated on:

- 1 Map servers: Installation, monitoring and maintenance of map servers and georeferenced data under **Geoserver** technology. Implementation in diverse ecosystems such as **Docker**, JAVA Servlet under **Apache Tomcat** or compiled **Jetty** environment.
- 2 Interactive Maps: Interactive map development for elementary and high school students usage. It allows students to perform measures, draw lines and write notations on blank maps to be saved as PDF files or printed on paper. http://mapasescolares.ign.gob.ar/
- 3 Geographic Data Publication: Instalation, migration and maintenance of Geonde. http://qhapaqnan.ign.gob.ar/
- 4 Rancher (Docker orchestration) The challenge was to discover every micro-service of a complete and vast stack to achieve 3 separate tasks:
 - Identify both github and dockerhub repositories for each stack component.
 - Identify every technology integrated in the system and define which technical profiles where required for the next development stages.
 - Write and expand documentation for every micro-service and pipeline.
- 5 Processes analysis: Deployment process analysis to increase stability and reliability, accommodate backup instances, rollbacks and other desired improvements.
- Web Page data capture: Data capture automation using Selenium + Python technologies, it extracts data which only can be retrieved by navigating a web page. Tasks include
 - user authentication
 - menu navigation,
 - file downloads and migrate data from downloaded files into a database.
- 7 Geoserver / Geonode instalation and fine tuning for heavy load.
 - http://wms.ign.gob.ar
 - http://qhapaqnan.ign.gob.ar
- 8 Joomla! / Drupal components adaptation.

pre-Production orchestration at TSOFT (for TELECOM S.A.)

October 2014 - February 2015 (5 months)

SeleniumHQ/ Javascript / Bash / SOAPUI developer with assertions-driven regression detection

- 2 Jenkins administration and unit test configuration
- 3 Coordination between various Software Factories, deployment areas and QA teams.

My responsibilities working at TELECOM S.A (as a TSOFT subcontractor) include:

- 1. Maintenance of Jenkins CI platform, it executes unit tests on Selenium, SoapAPI, Bash, HttpRequest to validate malfunctions on satellite applications, IBM's WebSphere message connectors deployed to the proper environments and fix WebSphere workers overflow events by automatically restarting them.
- 2. Coordinate with Software factories, Base infrastructure deployment areas and WebSphere administrators to ensure configurations and data / code migrations deployed to desired environment on schedule for every particular Release Candidate QA.

Desarrollador en 4IT

Diciembre de 2012 - Agosto de 2014 (1 año 9 meses)

El desafío fue reconstruir las relaciones entre los datos provenientes de sistemas descentralizados. Desarrollador Javascript / SQL / Qlikview en 4 IT para el Banco BIND. Desarrollamos un Data Warehouse que consume los datos del core bancario y los sistemas satélites y los almacena en una base de datos relacional MySQL. La etapa final se centralizo en explotar los datos con tecnología de análisis Big data qliqview.

Programador en TECENG GAMING Diciembre de 2011 - Noviembre de 2012 (1 año)

Diseño e implementación de herramientas para la gestión del soporte a usuarios. Desarrollo de procedimientos para la solución de problemas. Creación de manuales de uso interno. Análisis de datos sobre PostgreSQL con el objetivo de encontrar las causas de desvíos en la ganancia de los Slots Machine y determinar si fue producto de uso fraudulento

Proamador, Help Desk en TECENG GAMING Marzo de 2010 - Diciembre de 2011 (1 año 10 meses)

Soporte a usuarios en la utilización de un sistema propio de la empresa. Gestión de redes (administración remota de switch y equipos de interfaz con máquinas tragamonedas- SLOTS). Creación y documentación de procedimientos para la corrección de errores con las herramientas existentes del sistema.

Creación de scripts en bash.

Mantenimiento de bases de datos PostgreSQL

Empleado en Arwen

Marzo de 2003 - Enero de 2010 (6 años 11 meses)

Automatización de procesos productivos, programación de herramientas de control de stock y

facturación.

Soporte en Tecnet S.A.

Mayo de 2001 - Febrero de 2003 (1 año 10 meses)

Help Desk Windows, Lotus Notes y paquete Office, reparación de PC. El último año me encargue de la administración de servidores Novell.

Técnico en Wober y Asoc.

Marzo de 1999 - Abril de 2001 (2 años 2 meses)

Help Desk, reparación de PC e impresoras. Tendidos de red.

Educación

Universidad Nacional de Tres de Febrero

Licenciatura en Sistemas de Información Geográfica. 2019 - Actualidad

ET Nº 28 REPUBLICA FRANCESA

Técnico, Electrónica, 1994 - 1999

Gonzalo Varela

Analista Programador

gonzalo.varela1981@gmail.com



3 personas han recomendado a Gonzalo

"Recomiendo a Gonzalo Varela por ser una persona capaz en el sentido Laboral y Humano, ya que se integra de manera muy rápida al grupo y posee facilidad de aprendizaje, es un muy buen trabajador."

— Alfredo Cabezas, Técnico, Tecnet, ha trabajado directamente con Gonzalo en Tecnet S.A..

"Gonzalo es un excelente profesional y correcta persona, tuve la suerte de trabajar con el en distintos proyectos. Maneja muy bien las relaciones interpersonal adaptándose muy bien a los distintos grupos de

trabajo, tiene facilidad para de aprendizaje."

— Bruno J. Bosco Tmanager IT ISSUING PROCESSING supervisó a Gonzalo en 4IT..

"Es un gusto trabajar con Gonzalo. Se ha hecho cargo de la coordinación técnica del equipo de desarrollo de Ingeniería de Datos con mucha idoneidad, no sólo desde su conocimiento de las tecnologías y de las soluciones que desarrolla y mantiene el área, sino también desde el abordaje humano del equipo. Es un equipo que ha encarado procesos complejos de implementaciones, de resolución de incidentes y de desarrollo de soluciones en medio de una transición de referentes y bajo gran presión, y Gonzalo ha sabido aportar claridad, eficacia y buena coordinación de los colaboradores. Confío plenamente en su criterio técnico, y me da gusto compartir el día a día de trabajo con él."

— Rocío Marcalain, Directora General de Arquitectura de Datos, ha ocupado Gonzalo en Tecnet S.A..